海莉 你爸爸打电话来了
Haley, your dad's on the phone.
他说很紧急
He says it's urgent.
-他跟"外科医生"吗 -我觉得他说的是"鲟鱼"
- He's with a surgeon? - I think he said "sturgeon."
小卡 你说的是"外科医生"还是"鲟鱼"
Cam, is it "surgeon" or "sturgeon"?
我一回家就要把这该死的牙箍摘掉
I am ripping these stupid braces off the second I get home.
菲尔 别挂 我开免提 好吗
Phil, hold on. I'm gonna put you on speakerphone, okay?
安迪要去跟贝丝求婚了
Andy's on his way to propose to Beth!
我们什么都听不到
We can't hear anything!
把电话扔给我吧
Just toss me the phone.
-别别别 -你说得对
- No! No, no. - No, you're right.
我们都有自己的强项 我擅长送礼
We all have our strengths. I'm a great gift giver.
扔过来 小卡
Here, Cam.
-老爸 -海莉 安迪要去跟贝丝求婚了
- Dad? - Haley, Andy's on his way to propose to Beth!
-那好棒呀 -一点也不棒
- That's very sweet! - It's not sweet!
海莉和安迪彼此相爱 但他们却不知道
Haley and Andy love each other, but they don't know it!
是吗 亲爱的
Is that true, honey?
老爸 你凭什么觉得他爱上我了
Dad, what makes you think he's in love with me?
我看他跟你拥抱道别的样子就知道了
I could tell by the way he hugged you goodbye.
菲尔 你确定吗
Phil, are you sure about this?
克莱尔 我看得出男人眼里充满爱的模样
Claire, I think I know the look of love in another man's eyes.
太夸张了 我该给他打电话吗
This is crazy. Should I call him?
他的手机关机了 但他说他要去沙滩
His phone's off, but he said he was going to the beach.
我知道他喜欢哪个沙滩
I know what beach he likes.
我以为你就是他喜欢的"沙滩"[妞]
I thought you were the "Beach" he likes.
天啊 他们在那里
Oh, God, there they are.
我该过去吗 我不该过去
Should I do this? I shouldn't do this.
我过去了
I'm gonna do this.
什...亲爱的 亲爱的 等等 等等
W-- honey, honey, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
你必须百分百确定才行
You got to be really sure of this.
你过去拆散他们是为了什么
You're gonna go over there and break them up for what?
就为了跟他瞎玩玩 直到下一个人出现吗
To hang out or to date until the next guy comes along?
谁知道 但我们难道不该试试是否是真爱吗
Who knows? But shouldn't we get a chance to find out what we are?
我只是说你要看长远一点
I'm just saying look down the road a little.
你才21岁 而那个家伙看样子
You're 21, and that looks like a guy
已经准备好安定下来了
who is ready to settle down.
-是啊 -好吧...
- Yeah. - Well, um...
看来他已经替我做好了决定
I guess it's decided for me.
我觉得自己真是个傻瓜
I feel like such an idiot.
不 亲爱的 不不不
No. Honey, no, no, no, no, no.
你没什么好羞耻的
You have nothing to be ashamed of.
天啊 他们来了 快藏起来
Oh, God! Here they come! Hide!
就...
Just --
天啊
Oh, God.
小爸看起来好紧绷
Daddy looks tense.
他只是要付账单了
He's just paying bills.
还好吗 亲爱的
Is everything okay, honey?
你走过来的呀
Oh, you walked over here.
我还以为你上哪儿都打优步呢
I just thought you Uber-ed everywhere.
-好吧 -好吧 我得呼吸一下
- Okay. - Okay, I got to breathe.
这还是免费的吧
That's still free, isn't it?
米奇尔 没那么糟啦
Mitchell, it's not that bad.
真的吗 因为我好几周没工作了
Really? Because I haven't worked in weeks.
前途渺茫
I have no prospects.
我们靠着一个体育老师的工资生活
We're living off of a gym teacher's salary,
然后我还不知道哪根筋搭错了
And -- and somehow I let you
被你说服买下了楼上的房子
talk me into buying the apartment upstairs.
这是什么情况 我们变穷人了吗
What's going on? Are we poor?
不 但你小爸在找工作的期间
No, while other daddy looks for a job,
我决定去当
I'm gonna be taking on some work
暑期驾驶教练
as a summertime driver's ed teacher.
那能挣多少钱
How much can that pay?
聚沙成塔
Every little bit helps.
而且 米奇尔 在你意识过来前
And besides, Mitchell, before you know it,
你很快就会回到一间无聊的办公室
you're gonna be back in a stuffy office
跟一群无聊的律师在一起
with some stuffy lawyers,
后悔自己没有好好利用这段时间
wishing you had taken advantage of this time.
我说得对吗
Am I right?
听起来倒很像我
Well, that doesn't not sound like me.
没错 所以你为什么不利用这次机会
Exactly, so why don't you take this chance...
做点好玩的事情 找个爱好呢
...to do something fun, find a hobby?
每次我们去美术馆 你总会说
You know, every time we go to a gallery, you always say,
"这么蠢的东西我也会画啊"
"I could paint something that stupid."
那就证明一下吧
Well, prove it.
其实还真是 我一直很想画画
You know what? I have. I've always wanted to paint.
我们楼上的屋子也肯定很多人会抢着租
And the place upstairs is gonna be a rental gold mine --
只等我们刷上漆 配上家具 修好电路
Once we paint it, we furnish it, we fix the electric,
重新铺好水管
redo the plumbing,
搞清楚那块棕色斑点为何还在变大就行
and figure out why that brown spot won't stop growing.
它还长大了吗
It's growing?
你们俩浪费了一整天缝花被子吗
Did you two really just waste your entire day quilting?
我们玩得很开心啊 是吧 亲爱的
We had a wonderful time, didn't we, sweetie?
我没有再哭了
I'm not crying anymore.
为了让她停止想安迪
To help get her mind off of Andy,
海莉和我在做一件花被子
Haley and I have been making a quilt
用的是她的旧衣服...
out of all her old clothes...
和一些我不想让菲尔再穿的东西
and some stuff I need Phil to stop wearing.
酷 那块方形跟我的袋鼠牌帽子花纹一样
Oh, cool. That square is the same pattern as my kangol hat.
你们知道外面有多美吗
Can you believe how gorgeous it is outside?
现在里面也很美
And now it's gorgeous inside.
因为你在里面 我表达清楚吗
Because you're inside. Was that clear?
你想来考考我元素周期表吗
Hey, do you want to go quiz me on the periodic table?
氧钾
Oxygen potassium.
他用这两个元素说"OK"
He used the elements to say "Okay."
看完之后特"开心"啊
Well, that was fun for me.
妈 我们可以现在喝酒吗
Mom, can we drink now?
亲爱的 现在是午餐时间
Honey, it's lunchtime.
那就是说行
That's a "Yes."
我为什么觉得你很享受
Why do I feel like you're enjoying this?
-什么 -伤心的海莉又需要她妈妈了
- What? - Sad Haley needs her mommy again.
真荒唐
That's ridiculous.
我只是在帮她化心碎为力量
I'm just helping her channel her broken heart
改去做一些积极的事
into something more positive.
拜托 那是自艾滋病被子之后
Please, that's the saddest blanket
最悲哀的一块花被子了
since the AIDS quilt.
海莉沉溺于自怜之中 而你以此为生
Haley's wallowing in self-pity, and you're feeding off of it.
你不知道自己在说什么
You don't know what you're talking about.
妈妈 我要去午睡了
Mom, I'm just gonna go take a nap.
亲爱的 你想让我抱着你
Oh, sweetheart, do you want me to snuggle with you
陪你睡着吗
till you fall asleep?
够了 失恋派对结束了
Okay, that's it. Pity party's over.
该来点邓菲家的娱乐了 我们去看电影
Time for some Dunphy fun. We are going to the movies.
你上次洗澡是什么时候
When was the last time you showered?
今天是几号
What day is it?
我们等你
We will wait.
我知道你不能告诉我 但那个B·威利斯攀爬架
I know you can't tell me, but that B. Willis jungle gym --
是演员布鲁斯·威利斯对吗
That's Bruce Willis, right?
他的孩子们也在这上学吗
His kid goes here?
本校以保密而著称
Well, we do pride ourselves on privacy here at Davenport,
但你的"灵异第六感"很准哦[布鲁斯的电影]
but, uh, you may have a "Sixth Sense" about this.
太棒了
I'll be damned.
他看起来像是那种
He looks like the kind of guy
你想跟他来杯啤酒的人
you want to have a beer with, you know?
我们给每四个小孩配备一个老师
We have one educator for every four children --
我有个问题
I have a question.
我跟你们这里的一个毕业生是高中同学
Uh, I attend high school with one of your graduates,
他叫西欧多尔·德卡斯
a Theodore Durkas.
是你把他教成了禽兽 还是他从小如此
Did you turn him into a monster, or was he always like that?
我还真记得泰迪·德卡斯
I actually remember Teddy Durkas.
他是个可爱的小男孩
He was a lovely boy.
下次他把我的乳头掐紫时
I'll give him your regards
我会替你问候他的
next time he's making one of my nurples purple.
乔 你做了什么
Ay, Joe, what did you do?!
不是他的错
Oh, it's not his fault.
这些柜子是之前一个家长捐的
These cubbies were donated by a former parent
他觉得自己是个木匠
who fancied himself a carpenter.
我不能说是谁 但是这很讽刺
I can't say who, but it is ironic
他不懂怎么用铁锤 我们也"不能碰这个"了
that he couldn't use a hammer, and now we "Can't touch this."
你一直说你不能说 然后你又说出来了
You keep saying you can't say, and then you say.
难得能跟成年人说话太幸福了嘛
It's just nice to talk to adults.
我们愿意了 你想要乔吗 他归你们了
We're sold. You want Joe? He's yours.
你们真是太聪明了 提前预定明年
It was very smart of you to get a jump on next year.
明年 今年呢
Next year? What -- what about this year?
我们这里注册起码排到隔年
We enroll at least a year out.
就算是提早 等待名单也超长
And even then, there's a significant waiting list.
-你开玩笑吧 -抱歉 普里契特先生
- You're kidding. - I'm sorry, Mr. Pritchett.
你可以去学习谷仓看看啊
You could try the Learnin' Barn.
听起来不错
Ah, yes. That sounds very nice.
学习谷仓听起来不错吗
The Learnin' Barn sounds nice?
是啊 在我的村子里 只有富裕的孩子
Yes, in my village, only the richest kids
才能在谷仓里学习
were allowed to learn inside the barn.
希望你们喜欢恐龙
Hope you guys like dinosaurs.
我给我们买了《涉外大饭店2》的票
I got us tickets to "The second best exotic Marigold hotel."
我知道你在开玩笑
I know you're kidding,
但是我觉得第一部超感人
but I found the first one incredibly moving.
我从没意识到商场里有多少人牵着手
I never realized how many people hold hands in malls.
现在同性恋合法了
And now that gays are legal or whatever,
基本上所有人都牵着手
it's basically everyone.
亲爱的 我来牵着你的手 来吧
Honey, I'll hold your hand. Come here.
那是迪兰吗
Is that Dylan?
不 那绝对不是迪兰
No. No, that's -- that's definitely not Dylan.
迪兰
Dylan!
好啊 邓菲一家
Hello, Dunphy family!
真巧啊
What the what?
你好吗 孩子
How you doing, buddy?
生活是一辆过山车 但我够高了 可以乘坐
Life's a roller coaster, but I'm tall enough to ride.
同意
True dat.
海莉 你看起来一如既往的美丽
Haley, you look as yummy as ever.
谢谢 你在忙什么呢
Thanks. What's going on?
我现在在设计T恤
So, I'm designing t-shirts now,
想说服商店卖我的T恤
and I'm trying to get the stores to sell them.
我穿的就是呢
I'm wearing one.
-撒谎吗 -是生活
- "Lie"? - "Live."
V领也代表一个字母
The neck is the "V."
跨时代创意啊
Game changer.
是啊 我还有很多很棒的带V的词语
Yeah, and I've got all these great "V" words.
爱情 鸽子
"Love," "Dove" --
-走开 -州长
- Leave. - ..."Governor."
这主意真棒
That is such a cool idea.
真高兴见到你
It's so good to see you.
你想抽空喝杯咖啡吗
Do you want to get some coffee sometime?
我现在就没事啊
I'm not doing anything right now.
看电影呢
Movie.
不错 但不是所有带V的词都有用 邓太太
Nice try, but not all "V" words work, Mrs. D.
你俩玩得开心哦
Have fun, you two.
你迪什么迪啊
"Dylan!"
米奇尔 你知道我们女儿在吃蕃茄酱三明治吗
Mitchell, are you aware our daughter's eating a ketchup sandwich?
真好 她找到吃的了
Good, she found something.
你今天没去买菜啊
So, you didn't go grocery shopping today.
我会去的 但我要先去做瑜伽
I am gonna go, but after yoga.
你应该跟我一起来
You should come with me,
因为你看起来真的很紧绷
'cause you seem really tense.
他们有那种五分钟的班
well, maybe they have a five-minute class
能挤进我橄榄球夏令营和驾校之间吗
I could sneak in between football camp and driver's ed?
不 我很为你和你的葡萄柚骄傲
No, I'm very proud of you and your grapefruit.
这是克莱斯勒大厦
Chrysler building.
米奇尔远比我想象中
Mitchell really embraced
更欣然地接受了
this whole "take a little break" thing
短暂休假这件事
far more than I expected.
可是这么多年来都是他在赚钱养家
But for years, he supported both of us
让我自由发展爱好
while I pursued my passions --
比如摄影 嘻哈舞 猎狐
photography, hip-hop dancing, fox hunting.
所以我没资格催他去找工作
So I couldn't be the one to tell him to get a job.
不过也许别人可以
But maybe somebody else could.
查理 我是卡梅伦
Charlie? It's -- it's, uh, Cameron.
我丈夫米奇尔曾为您工作过
My husband Mitchell used to work for you.
我记得你
I remember you.
真是惊喜啊
Yeah, what a nice surprise.
就是 真疯狂
I know! Crazy!
就跟我告诉米奇尔是鸡的那狐狸一样疯狂
Crazy like that fox I told Mitchell was chicken.
很明显吧 我跟踪了查理
Was it clear? I-I stalked Charlie.
我不敢相信
I can't believe it.
米奇尔和我昨天晚上还在谈论你
Mitchell and I were just talking about you last night.
你好吗
How are you?
我不想拿我的问题来打扰你
Well, I don't want to burden you with my problems.
不过我的游艇好像不够大了
I think I've outgrown my boat.
-米奇尔好吗 -他很好
- How is Mitchell? - He's fine.
实际上 他最近收到好几份工作邀请
Actually, he's fielding a few job offers right now,
但是遇到点小麻烦
and he's running into problems
因为他一直拿所有人跟你比
because he keeps comparing everyone to you.
有时候我都觉得
Sometimes I think the only thing
唯一能让他好受的办法
that's gonna make him feel better
是您再提供一份工作给他
is if you offered him another job.
什么 我愿意
What the hell? I'll do it.
-真的吗 -我要买一艘新游艇
- Really? - Yeah, I'm getting a new boat.
我会找米奇尔说的
And I will talk to Mitchell.
我怀念那张三美元
I miss that $3 bill.
你们安排好了分手时间
You scheduled your breakup?
对 劳动节 我回学校的日子
Yes, Labor Day. That's when I leave for school.
86%的长距离恋爱最终失败
86% of long-distance relationships end in failure.
这是唯一合理的行为
It's the only logical course of action.
这是我听过最不浪漫的事
That is the least romantic thing I've ever heard.
继续在一起啊
Stay together.
错了 应该分手
Wrong. Break up.
大学是世界上最诱人的糖果店
College is the sexiest candy store in the world.
你可不想闭紧着嘴巴进去
You don't want to show up with your jaws wired shut.
不 就拿我跟海莉的经验来说
No, take it from Haley and me.
分开再在一起
It's hard to be apart and then together
再分开再在一起
and then apart and then together
再分开 被海军给拒了
and then apart and then turned down by the marines
再在一起 真的好难
and then together.
不敢相信那个傻瓜又回到我们的生活中
I can't believe we've got that dodo back in our lives.
至少海莉开心了
At least Haley's happy.
亲爱的 你至少把那T恤给脱了吧
Honey, could you at least take that T-shirt off?
熟食店里的人很喜欢 他们可得意了
They loved it at the deli. They were kvelling.
大家好
Hey-oh!
-安迪 -你好
- Andy! - Hi.
抱歉打扰了你们 我只是想把这些给你
Sorry to interrupt. I just want to get these to you.
-这是跟贝伍德的合约 -太棒了
- Here is the closing on Baywood. - Awesome.
这是强森的报价 只要签名就好
And this is the Johnsons' offer, all set for signatures.
你已经破茧成蝶了 哥们
You've done a real mitzvah, buddy.
希望还不错
I hope that's good.
好久没见过你了
I -- it's been awhile since I've seen you.
我多加了好多班
Yeah, I've been putting a lot of hours in,
为婚礼多赚些钱
trying to earn extra money for this wedding.
你好 我是迪兰 海莉的男朋友
Hola. I'm Dylan, Haley's boyfriend.
我是安迪 我不知道你们已经复合了
I'm Andy. I didn't realize you two are back together.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
我们就像磁铁一样
We're like magnets...
偶尔分开去约一下别的磁铁
that sometimes take a break to date other magnets.
我们在一起过
What happened was we were together,
然后分开了
and then we were apart.
感谢您今天花时间见我们
Thank you so much for making time for us today.
很抱歉花了这么长时间
I'm sorry it took so long,
教职员们都放暑假去了
but the faculty kind of scatters for the summer.
我开着我的卡车去缅因州种了豆子
I drove my van to Maine and planted beans.
让我猜猜 然后杀死了一个巨人
Let me guess -- and killed a giant.
-鸡 -这是怎么... 乔
- Chicken! - What the -- Joe!
乔 回来
Joe, come back here.
没关系 小鸡们不会伤到他的
It's okay. The chickens won't hurt him.
它们习惯了小孩子
They're used to the kids.
小鸡也是这里的一部分吗
Chickens are part of this?
我们喜欢尽量利用山里的一切
We like to utilize the setting here in the hills,
让自然成为体验的一部分
make nature a part of the experience.
我们偶尔会看到老鼠 浣熊或者小松鼠
We sometimes see mice or raccoons or little squirrels.
你知道还有专门捉这些的陷阱吧
You know they got traps for those kind of things.
我喜欢这里 乔能够在新鲜空气里奔跑
Ay, I love it. Joe gets to run around in the fresh air.
艾瑞卡 我需要你
Erica, I need you!
抱歉 失陪一下
I'm sorry. Excuse me.
我们要走了
We're out of here.
她很奇怪 让孩子们
She's a loon, letting kids call her "Erica"
像牌友一样直呼她艾瑞卡
like they're poker buddies.
这么晚我们去不了别的地方了
We're too late for anywhere else.
如果布鲁斯·威利斯能靠
If Bruce Willis can jungle-gym his way
捐攀爬架进高大上学校 那我也能...
into that fancy school, then I can...
我不知道 我能靠柜子进去
I don't know -- I can cubbie my way in.
他们不喜欢现在的柜子 我给他们做新的
They hate their cubbies? I'll make them new ones.
小柜子不就是小版衣柜嘛
Cubbies are nothing but little closets.
看看乔 他喜欢这里
Ay, but look at Joe. He loves it.
他正追鸡呢
He's chasing after the chickens.
他还逮到一只
He even caught one.
不 不
No! No!
别呀 乔 快放开
No, Joe! Let go!
我们很乐意付那只鸡的钱
We will be very happy to pay for that chicken.
米奇尔 米奇尔
Mitchell, Mitchell!
看看我一不小心还十分巧合得碰见了谁
Look who I bumped into accidentally by chance.
你好啊 陌生人
Hey, stranger.
查理
Charlie!
不知道你还会画画
I didn't know you painted.
其实我也不知道
I didn't, either.
刚开始只是为了消忧解闷
It sort of started as a therapeutic thing,
但后来就爱上它了
But then I just really fell for it.
我一直都想画画
I always wanted to paint.
我靠
Damn it!
我为什么不画画
Why am I not painting?
你管理公司很忙嘛
Well, you're so busy running your company.
要不多雇点人 这样你就有空了
Maybe if you hired more people, you'd have more time.
我睡了那么多演员模特
I sleep with so many actresses and models
她们喜欢有飞机 游艇和度假别墅的男人
who are into guys with jets and boats and ski houses,
但我一直在想 睡喜欢艺术家的
But I always wondered, wouldn't it be more satisfying
模特和演员肯定更来劲
To sleep with actresses and models who are into artists?
对了 你刚在说你被工作搞得喘不过气
Anyway, you were saying how overwhelmed you were at work.
这幅画才美得让我不能呼吸
I'm overwhelmed by this work.
你都怎么决定画什么的呢
How do you decide what to paint?
我脑子里有些画面
You know, I just see these images in my head,
比如说 我想看的东西 想去的地方
Uh, things I want to see, places I want to go,
还剩下多少颜料
how much paint I have left.
有些时候就跟着感觉走
sometimes I just tap into my emotions,
看看最后是什么效果
and I see where that takes me.
你都想不到整个人能有多满足
And -- you cannot imagine the sense of contentment.
想想工作一整天
Imagine how much more satisfying it would be
会有多爽吧
after a good day's work.
我来这里
You know, I came here to talk you
本是想让你回公司工作
into coming back to the company,
但你是我见过最波澜不惊的小伙
But you're the most at-peace son of a bitch I've ever met,
我可是请大喇嘛主持过泳池派对的人
And I hired the Dalai Lama for a pool party.
谢谢 长官
Thank you, commander.
出城的时候我会顺便送到办公室
I will drop these at the office on the way out of town.
还有什么事吗
So, unless there's something else?
你就是事 克莱尔赏他个杯子蛋糕
You're something else. Claire, get this man a cupcake.
不用了 邓菲夫人
No, thank you, Mrs. Dunphy.
我马上就要穿礼服了
I've got to fit into a wedding tux pretty soon.
好吧 你出发吧 骑车愉快
All right, get out of here. Happy motoring.
-再见 安迪 -再见
- Bye, Andy. - See you.
他要去哪
Where's he off to?
犹他州 去那一个月准备婚礼
Utah for a month to plan his wedding.
我好后悔 安迪很棒
I'm kicking myself. Andy is great.
要不是我多嘴
And if I hadn't opened my big, fat mouth,
也许海莉现在就和他在一起了 而不是迪兰
Haley might be with him right now instead of with Dylan.
-你想什么呢 -没什么
- What? - Nothing.
克莱尔
Claire?
我在想 假如安迪知道
Oh, I was just wondering what would happen
海莉差点... 会怎么样
if Andy were to find out that Haley almost --
我们不能插手
No. We are not meddling like that.
不 我们当然不会了
No, we're not. Of course we're not.
但是你插手了啊
But you meddled when you called Haley
你打电话告诉海莉安迪喜欢她
and told her that Andy liked her.
这跟告诉安迪
That's a far cry from telling Andy
海莉喜欢他
Haley was in love with him
还曾跑到海滩想阻止过求婚差远了
and raced to the beach to stop his proposal.
是卢克吗
Luke?
不是
Nope.
我不小心拿了你的笔
I accidentally took your pen.
我不想在规划自己婚礼的时候
And I didn't want to go plan my wedding
心里有这么大个包袱
with something so big weighing on my mind.
安迪 真抱歉
Andy, I am really sorry.
我不是故意让你听见的
I didn't mean for you to hear that.
别担心 没事
Do not worry. No big dip!
真的
Really?
Sure!
这其实挺好笑的
It's actually kind of funny, you know?
生活多疯狂啊
'Cause how crazy is life?
我一直在想 该向贝丝求婚吗
I was all, "Should I propose to Beth?
但我对其他人还有感觉
I have feelings for someone else."
我还想着海莉
Meantime, I was talking about Haley.
海莉很明显对我有感觉 我却不知道
Haley apparently had feelings for me, and I had no clue!
这难道不搞笑吗
How could you not laugh at something like that, right?
真好吃
So good.
好了 国庆节快乐
All right. Mmm. Happy Fourth.
我啥事没有
I am so fine.
-大伙好 -大家好
- Hey - Hello Hello
这东西放哪
Where do I put this?
放台子上就行 谢谢
Anywhere on the counter is great, thanks.
老爸
Hi, dad.
你胸口上是啥字
What's, uh, "E-olve" Mean?
是进化
Oh, no. It says "Evolve."
这是迪兰的设计 领口代替V字
It's one of Dylan's designs. The neck is the "V."
-这词里有两个V啊 -但人没有两个脖子啊
- There's two V's. - There can't be two necks.
-那为啥这么设计 -求别让我替他辩护
- Then why even do it? - Don't make me defend this, dad.
我就想做老好人
I am just trying to be supportive.
别理他 他这么暴躁
Ignore him. He's just grumpy
是因为乔明天要上学了
because Joe starts school tomorrow.
孩子们第一次离开家的时候
Well, that's hard when they leave the nest
的确挺让人难受的
for the first time.
我才不在乎那件事
I don't care about that.
我只是想靠东西不会掉出来的小柜子
All I wanted was to bribe my way into that fancy school
来疏通进那家高大上的学校
by making cubbies stuff didn't fall out of.
我们不能说太多 案子还在等结果
We can't say more. Litigation is pending.
好了 谁想吃我拿手的鸡肉沙拉
All right, who's ready for my famous chicken salad?
谢谢
Thank you!
-锡纸记得还我们 -好的
- We need the foil back. - Right.
你的耳朵怎么了 梵高
What happened to your ear, Van Gogh?
我在外面画向日葵的时候
I was painting sunflowers outside,
被蜜蜂叮了
and I got stung by a bee.
我觉得那是对我绘画水平的赞赏
You know, I take it as a compliment.
来自蜜蜂界的赞赏吗
From the bee community?
天啊 克莱尔 那是我的画
Oh, my goodness, Claire. That's one of mine.
-是的 -那幅画挂在那里太美了
- Yes, it is. - Oh, that looks so good there.
是吧 所有颜色我都喜欢 让我心旷神怡
Right? I just love all the colors. It makes me feel so happy.
是啊
Yeah.
我管它叫"移民者的掠夺"
I call it "Rape of the immigrant."
布朗尼蛋糕好像忘在车里了
I think we left the brownies in the car.
-我去拿 -去吧 伙计
- I'll get those. - Well, way to go, pal.
好了 你们到底是怎么回事
Okay, what is wrong with you people?
我都快死了 拼命干着两份工作
I am dying here, trying to hold down two jobs
而你们却任由一个曾经意气风发的人
while you enable a once-proud man
浪费才能做些毫无意义的傻事
who is clearly having a talent-free breakdown.
你知道为什么他让你想到梵高吗
You know why he reminds you of Van Gogh?
因为他不赚半毛钱
It's because he's earning nothing,
而且他就要疯了
and he's losing his mind!
各位 猜谁回来了
Hey, everybody! Guess who's back?!
谁 谁回来了
Who? Who is back?
安迪
Andy.
安迪 抱歉 一下子没认出你来
Andy! Sorry, it took me a second.
没关系 我知道 我的发型有些不一样
No, I know. I -- I'm parting my hair a little differently.
-是啊 -这是我的新变化之一
- Yeah. - That's one thing that's new about me.
贝丝喜欢我这样
So, Beth likes it this way.
-我喜欢 挺不错的 -挺好的
- I-I love it, looks great. - It looks great.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
米奇尔叔叔
Hi, Uncle Mitchell.
宝贝 怎么了
Honey, what's wrong?
没什么 我刚送走桑杰
Nothing. I-I-I just said goodbye to Sanjay.
我们分手了
We broke up.
不
No.
没关系 这很好
No, it's -- it's -- it's great.
我们 我们都想没有负担的回到学校
We're -- we're both going to school unencumbered
专心于学业
and ready to focus.
这才是明智之举
It's the smart thing to do.
我们都十分满意这个做法
We both feel really good about it.
可你看起来并不好
You don't look like you feel good.
是啊 他比我想象得要伤心
Well, yeah, he was -- he was sadder than I imagined,
所以我必须为了他而坚强起来
so I'm being strong for the both of us,
这正是他欣赏我的地方
which he said he admires.
我想是吧
I think.
听着他那些约翰传奇的歌
It was hard to hear him
还有抽噎声 我听不太清他说的话
with all the John Legend and the sobbing.
你知道吗
You know what?
我最近也经历了一段很难熬的日子
I recently went through a very hard time,
而我发现了一种非常有助于
and I found something that really helped me
排遣消极情绪的方法
navigate my feelings.
-我不想画画 -绘画
- I don't want to paint. - Painting.
天啊 是不是
Oh, my God, right?
我要吓疯了
I am freaking out.
你觉得他是因为听到我们的谈话才那样的吗
You don't think that's because of what he heard us say, do you?
不 很多人订婚以后都会发胖
No, lots of people gain weight during their engagement.
-你就是 -我当时怀孕了
- You did. - I was pregnant.
我在努力想理由呢 克莱尔
I'm trying, Claire.
我不想相信我们是害他成这样的元凶
I don't want to believe we're responsible.
他当然是因为我们才这样的
Of course we're responsible.
很明显 安迪自从发现海莉曾试图
Clearly, Andy has been stuffing his face
阻止他求婚 就开始暴饮暴食
ever since he found out that Haley almost stopped his proposal.
什么
What?
我们以后真应该在车库里说话了
We have got to start talking in the garage.
迪兰 你能为我做个盘子吗
Dylan, could you make me a plate?
如果我都能用胡萝卜做出一杆烟枪
If I can make a bong out of a carrot,
那我肯定能为你做个盘子
I think I can make you a plate.
你告诉安迪我曾试图阻止他求婚吗
You told Andy I tried to stop his proposal?
不是故意的
Not on purpose.
在他去犹他州前夕 你父亲和我
Before he left for Utah, your father and I
私下里在讨论 如果被他发现
were privately discussing how bad it would be
情况会有多糟糕 结果被安迪听见了
if he found out, and Andy overheard us.
他当时说什么了
What did he say?
他说他没事
He said he was fine.
可是... 现在我们不太肯定了
But...now we're not so sure.
天啊
Oh, my God.
天啊 那是安迪吗
Oh, my God, that's Andy?
你们觉得他是因为我才胖成那样的吗
You think he got fat 'cause of me?
也许吧 是的
Possibly. Yes.
我该去跟他谈谈吗
Should I talk to him about it?
宝贝 那得由你自己来决定
Honey, that has to be your decision.
我们不想再干涉你的感情生活了
We are through meddling in your love life.
是的 不过我要说 他依然有婚约在身
Yeah. Though I will say he's still very much engaged.
如果是我呢 我会想知道
Whereas, I would want to know if he got fat
他发胖是否因为依然爱着我
because he was still in love with me.
现在我们走了
And now we're out.
你看 是不是舒服多了
See, don't you feel better?
没有
No.
别纠结于光线
Don't stress out about light
景致 还有颜色
and perspective and -- and color.
知道吗 就随心所欲地画出想表达的东西
You know, just let your painting be what it wants to be.
-怎么样 -让我看看
- How's this? - Here, let's see.
搞什么鬼 你怎么画得这么好啊
What the hell? Why are you so good?
我也不知道 我大部分事情都很擅长
I don't know. I'm just good at most things.
通常我也是啊
So am I, usually.
等等 桑杰也是这样
Wait a second. So is Sanjay.
我得在他走之前赶紧去找他
I-I-I-I have to get to him before he leaves.
-你真的画得越来越好了 -你还是进屋去吧
- You're really getting better. - Maybe you should go inside.
乔 乔 乔 赶紧给我下来
Joe, Joe, Joe, Joe, get down from there!
-你会受伤的 -发生什么事了
- You're gonna get hurt. - What happened?
这就是他不该去你那家公立幼儿园的原因
This is why he shouldn't go to your commune.
他会摔下来 那些嬉皮士根本注意不到
He'll fall, those hippies won't notice,
他会被鸡给生吞活剥了的
And he'll be eaten alive by chickens.
我想我们已经确定过
I think we have established
在鸡面前 他完全可以保护好自己的
That he can take care of himself around a chicken.
你老是忘记乔很强悍 他也遗传自我
You keep forgetting that Joe is tough. He's part me.
你该担心的是你那个儿子
That's the son that you should be worrying about.
我曾以为可以不用再管那个儿子了
I really thought I was done with that one.
你还好吗
How's it going?
我受了点小伤 以及其他一些问题
I got a splinter... and a few other issues.
你知道这是什么情况吧
You know what's happening here, don't you?
你遭遇中年危机了
You're having a mid-life crisis.
天啊
Oh, my god.
有些人通过开快车 找小三解决
Some guys, it's fast cars and women.
我 是打高尔夫
Me, it was golf.
你 则成了基佬中的战斗基
You, it's just a little gayer.
我认识大约10个高尔夫球打得比你好的拉拉
I know like 10 lesbians who could out-golf you.
重点是 如果你的那根弦绷得太紧
The point is when you're wound as tight as we are,
是会断的
You're bound to snap.
是啊 太长时间以来我都十分拼命地工作
Yeah, I-I've just been working so hard for so long.
然后我突然停下来了
And now that I've stopped,
我 我就难以再重新开始了
I'm -- I'm having a hard time starting again.
我懂的
Oh, I get it.
我有一年夏天休假6周专门去打高尔夫
I took six weeks off one summer just to play golf.
有一天 在俱乐部联赛中
And one day, during the big club tournament,
我把一根7号铁球棒挥出了界外
I hooked a seven-iron out of bounds.
我气坏了 把球棒绑在一棵树上
I got so pissed that I wrapped the club around a tree
然后把一台高尔夫车从桥上开进湖里
And drove the golf cart off the little bridge into the lake.
我永远无法忘记那位驻场选手对我说的话
I'll never forget what the club pro said to me.
"普里契特先生 你不是个好的高尔夫球手
"Mr. Pritchett, you're not a very good golfer.
回去干你的正经工作吧"
Go back to your day job."
我知道我不是个好画家 爸
I know I'm not a good painter, dad.
我 我只是希望在回去工作前
I -- I was just hoping to feel a little bit better
先让自己感觉好一些
Before going back to work.
你只有回去工作了 才会感觉好一些
You're not gonna feel better until you go back to work.
米奇尔 你是个出色的律师
Mitchell, you're a great lawyer.
继续去当律师吧
Go do that.
还有去把头发剪剪
And get a haircut.
听着 我听说你发现了
So, listen, um, I heard that you found out
我那天其实去了海滩
That I was at the beach that day.
是啊
Yeah.
我之前不知道你对我是那种感觉
I didn't know you felt that way about me.
如果那时候知道就好了
Would have been nice to know.
那时如果知道你对我也有感觉就好了
Well, it would have been nice to know you had feelings for me.
那样 很多事情都会变得无比美好
A lot of things would have been nice.
你现在对我有感觉吗
Do you have feelings for me now?
海莉 我已经订婚了
Haley, I'm engaged.
你没有正面回答我
That's not an answer.
你为什么选择现在来谈这事啊
Why are you picking now to talk about all this?
因为我担心你这样
Because I'm worried about all this.
什么啊 我的体重吗
What? My weight?
拜托 我分分钟就能减肥成功
Please. This will drop off in a second.
安迪 你觉不觉得有这么一种可能
Andy, don't you think that there is a chance
就是你现在暴饮暴食
That you have been eating
是因为你后悔跟贝丝订婚了
Because you regret getting engaged to Beth?
我为什么要后悔啊 贝丝超赞的
Why would I do that? Beth is amazing.
贝丝是个试图点燃我头发的神经病
Beth is a psycho who tried to light my hair on fire.
然而 迪兰现在正在后院
Meanwhile, Dylan is in the backyard
试图用小棍棒做个盘子呢
Trying to make a plate out of sticks.
至少他知道自己想要什么 然后就努力去追求了
Well, at least he knows what he wants and goes for it.
那我觉得我们没在一起真是好事呢
Then I guess it's a good thing that we didn't get together.
真是我做过的最明智的决定
Best decision I ever made!
我也是
Samesies!
我不打算说谎 菲尔
I'm not gonna lie, Phil.
我或许不得不插手了
I might need to get back into that.
桑杰
Sanjay!
天啊 我无法承受再次道别
Oh, god. I can't say goodbye again.
我们不必道别的
We don't have to.
我们这个决定是根据统计数据而做出的
We're basing this decision on a statistic.
86%的异地恋都以失败告终 对吧
86% of long-distance relationships end in failure, correct?
当然对了
Of course "correct."
你向来都不会错误引用数据的
You'd never misquote a statistic.
你也不会的
And neither would you.
我们有哪方面是在落后的那86%的群体中啊
When have we ever been in the bottom 86% percentile of anything?
从没有 那样我情愿去死
Never. I'd kill myself.
我们属于那顶尖的1%
We're in the top 1%.
没错 我只用了一个下午就学会了画画
Exactly. I learned how to paint in an afternoon.
昨晚 我开发了一个App
Last night, I developed an app
可以从大学里远端喂我的鱼
to feed my fish from college.
如果说有人能异地恋成功 那就是你和我了
If anyone can make this work, it's you and me.
天啊 我好爱数字
God, I love numbers.
我也好爱数字
I love numbers too.